To my parents, Pepe and Carmina.
Simply, because I love you.
And like always to Pau, my great love.
redención
Del lat. redemptio, -ōnis.
Acción y efecto redimir.
redimir
Del lat. redimĕre.
Rescatar o sacar de esclavitud al cautivo mediante precio.
MUSIC BOX STARTS PLAYING SLOWLY:
"Für Elise" by Beethoven
[BOX CLOSES, MUSIC STOPS]
Dad, tell me the story of Pau Outoftime.
Again?
Yeees!
You already know it by heart!
Please!
[Grunts]
Alright...
Let's see... How did it start?
[Ominous music]
Once upon a time, there was a man
who didn't know how to enjoy his free time.
Although in fact
he didn't have any.
Pau Outoftime was his name
A day like any other, he decided
to change the stress of the city
for the peace of a rural life
where he, still, continued to
suffer from stress.
He had everything anyone could ever wish
but he couldn't make any of it
He spent all day writing non stop
in order to fulfill his readers needs
neglecting the ones from his loved ones.
Pau Outoftime's wife
who, in past times, had been
the prettiest and most cheerful girl in town
had become an elusive and grim woman
from the moment the doctors had diagnosed the sadness illness
which they didn't know anything about,
but they didn't hesitate to treat.
Here, baby.
Ok
Come, please
It was about time!
It's a good thing that you were going
to make her dinner tonight...
Paz, don't get started...
And this is it, day after day.
Is she feverish?
No, but at night there's more risk of it getting higher.
What's this? A preemtive war? Against your own daughter?
Keep the sarcasm, Pau.
It's just Dalsy. It is not arsenic...
Dalsy, Dalsy... Now you're being the sarcastic one...
That's what medicines are made for, Pau.
But you don't like progress.
If it were for you, we would still be in the 19th century.
It's enough
But you know what?
People back then died from a mere cold.
That's what you want for your daughter?
No, but I don't want her to be a drug addict like...
Say it
don't be shy
And please, don't pretend that you feel bad about it.
I think I'd better take the girl to sleep.
[SIGHS]
Come on
How are you feeling?
Muy bien.
Mmm
¿Seguro que no te duele nada?
No, estoy bien.
Ah
¡¡El cuento!!
Ay, Lis... Hoy no puedo. No tengo tiempo.
Mañana... ¿vale?
Siempre dises lo mismo...
Yeah...
But I can't today
I'll read it tomorrow, for sure, huh? Come on
Come
It's time to sleep. Come on
Sleep tight
Ready?
Good night.
[KISS]
[CLOCK TICKING]
You're already here?
I'm sure you didn't read the story to her
And you shouldn't be drinking that much
[SIGHS]
I feel very lonely here
I can't stand being here más tiempo
Tan alejada de todo y de todos
Oye mira siempre estás igual
s
[Sighs]
[Door slams]
Whispers: basta ya, basta yag
Paz
No me gusta lo que estás haciendo con Lis
no me gusta que tome una pastilla cada vez que tú tomas una…
Por favor...
¿Por qué siempre tienes que ser tan hiriente?
Encima es esta mañana todavía tenía fiebre.
Deja de...¡Ya basta! ¡Las pastillas te anulan! ¡Los medicamentos hacen que no seas tú!
¡Bebes demasiado!
Basta ya, Paz.
Venga, olvidemos todo esto y vámonos a cenar de una vez.
No!
No hay cena.
[Sobs]
¿No hay cena?
No hay cena, ¿no?
¿¡Ves por qué te lo digo!?
[Sobs]
[Sobbing]
Y así, día tras día
la relación de Pau Sintiempo con su mujer se fue resquebrajando.
[Crying]
golpes, ruidos, puerta?
Todo lo que en otros tiempos les unía
hasta el amor por su hija
fue deshilachándose poco a poco
Hasta que una fría y ventosa noche del mes de diciembre...
[Ominous music starts playing]
[Keys jingling? cuttlery?]